<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apache Security Team</title>
    <link>https://security.apache.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Apache Security Team</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://security.apache.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Processing, Compliance Statements and SLA</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/data-processing-compliance-statements-and-sla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/data-processing-compliance-statements-and-sla/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Software Foundation is a non commercial, open source organization that relies on a large community of volunteers and companies to maintain its software. It provides this software freely (and gratis) &amp;lsquo;as is&amp;rsquo; - as per its license.
As such we are not a &amp;lsquo;vendor&amp;rsquo; or a &amp;lsquo;supplier&amp;rsquo;, but a steward. While you agree to our aforementioned license agreement, the Apache Software Foundation does not commit to things that a vendor or supplier would usually commit to, such as providing a typical commercial helpdesk, commercial support, a 24x7 service level agreement and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS/OSTIF commission audit of three Apache Commons projects</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/commons-audit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/commons-audit/</guid>
      <description>The Open Source Technology Improvement Fund (OSTIF), funded by Amazon Web Services (AWS), recently commissioned an audit of three Apache Commons projects: Apache Commons Lang, Apache Commons IO and Apache Commons Codec. We are proud to announce that Ada Logics, who performed the audit, did not find any vulnerabilities.
The Apache Commons libraries are low-level building blocks, often used in internal applications on trusted input. As such, unless otherwise specified, it is the responsibility of the application invoking the libraries to make sure any untrusted parameters are sanitized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xz/liblzma/libarchive compromise</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/cve-2024-3094/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/cve-2024-3094/</guid>
      <description>At this time, we do not believe that ASF projects or ASF infrastructure are directly impacted by CVE-2024-3094. We have no indication that the person(s) responsible for the backdoor have contributed to any ASF projects. After our initial, risk-based triage, our security team is now working with each project&amp;rsquo;s oversight team (the PMC) to review their possible use of the xz library through dependency for a second level of scrutiny and review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits for finding security vulnerabilities</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/credits/</guid>
      <description>We highly appreciate everyone who responsibly reports security issues to us: a diverse mix of community members, independent security researchers, software auditing firms, etc.
When we release a fix for a vulnerability in one of our projects, we publish a security advisory crediting the reporter, and distribute it though various Apache mailinglists, oss-security and the CVE programme: this way, we proactively signal the urgency to upgrade to our users.
The Apache Software Foundation, being a volunteer organization, does not have a bug bounty program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASF Security Report: 2023</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/asf-security-report-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/asf-security-report-2023/</guid>
      <description>Background The security committee of The Apache Software Foundation (ASF) oversees and coordinates the initial triage, handling, and process around vulnerabilities across all of the 320+ Apache projects handling over 65 incoming emails a day. Established in 2002, we have a consistent process for how issues are handled, and this process includes how our projects must disclose security issues. We have a single paid person to help deal with incoming vulnerability handling work, with the rest of the team, including the VP, being volunteers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache vulnerability severity rating system</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/severityrating/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/severityrating/</guid>
      <description>When disclosing a security vulnerability in a previous version of an Apache software project, the project typically assigns a severity level such as &amp;ldquo;low&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;critical&amp;rdquo;. For most projects we&amp;rsquo;ve have never defined what those levels mean. In this blogpost we introduce a default severity rating system, based on the scales we&amp;rsquo;ve been using with some specific projects for a long time.
From the early days of the Apache HTTP Server project we assigned an impact rating to security flaws, designed to be &amp;ldquo;How worried should I be about this vulnerability&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASF Security Report: 2022</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/asf-security-report-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/asf-security-report-2022/</guid>
      <description>Background The security committee of The Apache Software Foundation (ASF) oversees and coordinates the handling of vulnerabilities across all of the 350+ Apache projects handling over 60 incoming emails a day. Established in 2002, we have a consistent process for how issues are handled, and this process includes how our projects must disclose security issues. During 2022, the ASF hired an administrator to help deal with incoming vulnerability handling work, with the rest of the team being volunteers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2022-42889: interpolations that allow RCE disabled in Commons Text 1.10.0</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/cve-2022-42889/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/cve-2022-42889/</guid>
      <description>On 2022-10-13, the Apache Commons Text team disclosed CVE-2022-42889. Key takeaways:
If you rely on software that uses a version of commons-text prior to 1.10.0, you are likely still not vulnerable: you are only affected when this software uses the StringSubstitutor API without properly sanitizing any untrusted input. If your own software uses commons-text, double-check whether it uses the StringSubstitutor API without properly sanitizing any untrusted input. If so, an update to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache projects affected by log4j CVE-2021-44228</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/blog/cve-2021-44228/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/blog/cve-2021-44228/</guid>
      <description>Project Status Apache Ant Not Affected, a deprecated module uses log4j 1.x Apache Archiva Affected, release 2.2.6 will address this Apache AsterixDB Affected, fixed in 0.9.7.1 Apache Calcite Avatica Affected, update to 1.20.0 Apache Camel Not affected Apache CloudStack Not Affected Apache Druid Affected, update to 0.22.1 Apache EventMesh Affected Apache Flink Affected, fixed in 1.14.2, 1.13.5, 1.12,7, 1.11.6 Apache Fortress Affected, update to 2.0.7 Apache Geode Affected, update to 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Security Mailinglist</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/mailinglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/mailinglist/</guid>
      <description>To privately disclose a security vulnerability in one of our projects, use this process.
To discuss ASF-wide security-related topics, join the public security-discuss mailinglist: read the archives and subscribe by emailing security-discuss-subscribe@community.apache.org. Once subscribed, you can send your mail to security-discuss@community.apache.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting security issues</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/report/</guid>
      <description>Please select:
Infrastructure Dependencies ASF code If you found a potential issue with ASF infrastructure such as the apache.org websites, email infrastructure or version control systems. If you found an advisory for a library in the dependency tree of an ASF project or artifact If you found a potential issue in the codebase of an ASF project If you do not want to report an issue in any of the three categories above, but instead have a question such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting security issues in ASF code</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/report-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/report-code/</guid>
      <description>We warmly welcome reports of potential security vulnerabilities in our codebases.
Only use the security contacts to report undisclosed security vulnerabilities in Apache projects and manage the process of fixing such vulnerabilities. We cannot accept regular bug reports or other security-related queries at these addresses. We will ignore mail sent to these addresses that does not relate to an undisclosed security problem in an Apache project.
Note that results from source code security analysis tools are not accepted without additional analysis showing the problem indeed violates the projects&amp;rsquo; security model, as such tools commonly produce a significant amount of false positives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting security issues in ASF infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/report-infra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/report-infra/</guid>
      <description>ASF infrastructure includes the apache.org websites, email infrastructure and version control systems.
There are some classes of common reports that we consider invalid up-front:
We already know our mailservers do not use DKIM/DMARC. We plan to support this in the future, but this is nontrivial given our strong reliance on mailinglists. As an open source organization with transparency at our core, read access to directory listings, source code repositories and build servers is intentionally public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reporting security issues in dependencies</title>
      <link>https://security.apache.org/report-dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://security.apache.org/report-dependency/</guid>
      <description>When an advisory is published for a library in the dependency tree of an ASF project or artifact, more often than not, the project does not use the dependency in a way that is affected by the problem described in the advisory. For this reason we don&amp;rsquo;t accept the simple fact that an advisory exists for a dependency as a vulnerability report in itself.
Practical steps you can take in this situation are:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
